this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software developers are you ready it's
time to upgrade your data platform to
inner systems iris choose your language
choose your tools choose your
environment collaborate build faster and
deploy more efficiently when you can
make faster decisions there's no telling
what you'll create ready set code start
coding for free visit inner systems comm
slash try to try iris for software
engineering radio this is Robert bloomin
I have with me today
Yevgeniy Brickman Evgeny is the
co-founder of grunt work a company that
provides a reusable library of
infrastructure code written in terraform
Go Python and bash previously of Guinea
was a software engineer at LinkedIn
TripAdvisor Cisco Systems and Thompson
financial he's the author of the
recently published book terraform up and
running and you can see his talk online
lessons learned from writing three
hundred thousand lines of infrastructure
code you've get a welcome to software
engineering radio thanks for having me
we will be talking today about
infrastructure as code design patterns
and best practices we've covered
infrastructure as code previously in
episode 268 and we'll also be
referencing material from 289 on
declarative programming in terraform
yvgeni I'd like to start out with a
brief review of the concept of
infrastructure as code what does that
mean to you I think a lot of it comes
from this lovely buzzword the DevOps
movement where you know in the past you
would have a dev team that would write
code write their apps you have an ops
team
would rack infrastructure rack servers
put things together in a physical data
center but these days that's changed
right all of the infrastructure these
days is living in the cloud at least
most companies are moving there and so
even the hardware that we're managing is
managed through software so the ops team
is writing code to manage all the
hardware and all the operations aspects
and so infrastructures code is just that
it's the ability to manage to deploy
manage all of your infrastructure using
code which has a lot of really really
nice properties you know if this is a
there's software engineers listening I
probably don't need to convince anybody
of the value of code but you know being
able to manage your infrastructure that
way rather than by clicking around
manually into UI or just running a bunch
of one-off commands using code Maiden's
things will deploy much faster much more
consistently it's a lot safer because
it's automated you're not relying on
some human memory to get something wrong
the Codex is documentation you can put
it in version control so you have the
whole history of what happened to your
infrastructure you can do automated
testing you can do code reviews you can
reuse code so you're not doing
everything from scratch every time and
possibly most importantly for me as a
software developer is I much prefer
writing and running code than doing a
bunch of stuff manually so being able to
manage my infrastructure by you know
running a terraform apply command just
makes me feel better than sitting for
two hours at the AWS console and mashing
up you know my mouse button for awhile
yeah your finger gets kind of tired when
you do that yeah as many of those points
you ran through we're going to be
expanding on those in more depth those
are things that you are well known to
software engineers but maybe newer to
the world of infrastructure and so I'm
going to circle back around to that as
part of the crowd worker could you
mention what are some of the main
infrastructure as code tools and
particularly emphasis on terraform
usually when I talk with people about
infrastructures code there's really four
broad categories of tools the first one
that a lot of people think of is just
whatever they think of when they think
automating anything which is let's just
go write a bunch of scripts so they bust
out in Ruby Python bash whatever your
favorite scripting languages and you
start writing code to do whatever it is
you need to do in the infrastructure
world which works well in some to some
extent you are automating things you are
capturing them as code but these tools
are not custom-built for managing
infrastructure you can write code in a
million different ways you get all these
weird patterns that are hard to follow
they don't take into account things like
item potency and what happens after the
initial deployment so usually ad hoc
scripts end up being a little bit of a
mess
the next category up from that are
configuration management tools that's
things like chef puppet ansible salt
that category of tools that started
appearing around I think 2008 or so and
so these are custom-built tools for
managing infrastructure and they build a
lot of things in that make it easier for
you so they have a certain structure
that they usually tell you to follow
they do take into account item potency
usually have less code to write because
the tools have lots of built-in helpers
and so they're pretty powerful and it's
usually a nice upgrade from just ad-hoc
script the biggest downside is that the
tools themselves get pretty complicated
and often to use them you have to run
extra infrastructure so for chef the
canonical wastes you have to have some
master nodes and that's extra stuff you
have to do and learn and maintain so
another way of managing the the software
that's on your servers that's becoming
more and more popular these days is to
use various types of images so there's
docker images those are containers and
VM images which to be fair have been
around for a while and the idea here is
rather than configuring a bunch of
servers that are already deployed you
actually create a single master image
this canonical hermetically-sealed
thing that represents how you want a
server configured and so that thing is a
docker image or VM and then you can take
this little image you can version it and
now you can use it all over the place
you can use it in all of your
environments testing
age production you can also run the same
code in dev which is pretty rare to do
with the other tools it's not common to
use chef or puppet on your own laptop
but running a docker image or even a VM
on your laptop is completely normal so
that's another way to manage your
infrastructure but all of these tools I
mentioned so far they're focused on ok I
have a server and I want to install you
know Linux on it and these five pieces
of software that I depend on question
then is how do you actually manage all
the infrastructure under the hood how do
you get those servers in the first place
and that's where provisioning tools come
in such as terraform and CloudFormation
and a few others and so these tools are
custom-built for defining the underlying
infrastructure layer that's all the
server's networking layer load balancing
databases DNS etc and these tools are
probably the newest of the bunch
I think terraform has been around since
maybe 2014 or so but they're filling a
very important niche which is as we move
to the cloud we need a way to manage all
of this underlying infrastructure Oscoda
and terraform has become very very
popular way for doing exactly that in
your book you provide some estimates for
how long it takes to develop
infrastructure as code projects from
scratch on first reading these they
seemed rather large but they're
consistent with my experience but I also
can't help thinking that it really
shouldn't take that long I want to start
out with give some numbers for how long
these projects take it certainly varies
on what you're doing and the the numbers
that I have in the book focused
specifically on somebody that wants to
use this infrastructure in production in
other words you're not building just a
side project this isn't just something
for your you know just for having fun
this is something you're betting your
company on right thousands millions
billions of dollars are at stake so if
you're going to production there are a
lot of things you have to take into
account and building all of that out
takes a significant amount of time rough
numbers and and to be honest these are
probably best-case scenarios but roughly
speaking if you are using the cloud
using AWS or Azure GCP and you're
using a managed service something where
the cloud provider has already done most
of the work you can probably get that
thing production ready in a couple weeks
but if you're using a cloud provider and
you're gonna be building your own
distributed system on there if that's
system as stateless
so it's not storing any data locally
it's maybe shoveling it out to some
database like a bunch of nodejs apps now
the amount of time it's gonna take you
to go to production will typically take
about twice as long so maybe four weeks
six weeks something like that
if the distributed system is stateful so
you want to spin up you know the ELQ
stack so elasticsearch log stash and
kobata
and these are all writing to disks and
you probably don't want to lose that
data now we're gonna go up a whole order
of magnitude now we're talkin one so
this could be two to four months to get
a system like that ready for production
and finally if you're gonna be spinning
up your entire cloud architecture so all
of these managed services your own
stateless distributed systems your
stateful distributed systems all the
wiring in between to connect everything
and see ICD pipelines and so on and so
forth we're talking six months minimum
to do it from scratch and for larger
companies usually a whole lot more 24
months 36 months would be pretty normal
do you think the time reflects the
complexity of what you're trying to do
or is it because these tools are don't
quite work as smoothly as possible and
you spend a lot of time fighting with
the tools in the environment I think
there's a lot of factors I I think the
two main ones that I've seen that cause
this stuff to take so long is one is
what you're mentioning so it comes down
to the tools and just the fact that
DevOps is new and so a lot of the tools
are fairly immature they're new there's
a lot of patterns we're still figuring
out and so for various reasons DevOps is
really susceptible to this concept that
is delightfully described as yak shaping
for people listening who have not heard
this term I think you're gonna enjoy it
this is one of my favorite terms and
anybody in the software industry is
gonna be very familiar with it so yak
shaving the idea here is it's all the
little things you have to do before you
get to work on the thing you actually
want it to do in the first place the
canonical example in my mind comes for
Seth Godin blog if he has a blog post
specifically about yak shaving and he
gives this kind of really wonderful
example where you know you wake up one
day and you decide okay I'm gonna go wax
my car today and you head outside you go
find the hose and you find out that the
hose is broken okay no problem you'll
run over to the hardware store get a new
hose so you get in your car you're just
about to head over the hardware store in
your eyes ah okay there's a bunch of
toll booths on the way I need one of
those easy pass things so I'm not
spending all my day paying tolls so you
look around for the easy pass can't find
it and say ah no problem I'll borrow the
easy pass from my neighbor you're just
about to head over to the neighbour's
house when you realize oh wait a minute
I just borrowed a bunch of pillows from
him last week I got to return those
first so then you go dig through your
house to find the pillows and you
realize all the hair all the yak hair
and those pillows has fallen out and so
the next thing you know you're at the
zoo shaving it yak also you can go and
wax your car so so that's yak shaving
right it's just all of this stuff you
have to do that seems to get in the way
and programming we see this a lot you
know you want it to go deploy some
simple piece of code and somehow two
weeks later you're fixing a TLS
certificate halfway across your codebase
but DevOps in particular seems
susceptible to this because I think the
tools are fairly primitive they're
really tightly coupled every you know
every time you touch something it feels
like pulling a a wire out of a box of
wires you know it kind of drags
everything else with it and so things
really take a lot longer than you expect
because of that yeah we've all been
there now we've reviewed some of the
problem domain I want to get into the
main focus of this talk you hit on some
of these in your intro the software
engineering community has developed a
lot of knowledge about software
development best practices some of which
could be applied to infrastructure as
code and that's one of the main focuses
of your book I'd want to start out with
the idea of modules
why do you advise the use of modules in
terraform so modules and terraform are
very similar to functions or classes in
a general-purpose programming languages
if using Java or C or Python you're
probably used to breaking your code up
into a bunch of small functions and
so in terraform breaking things up into
modules pretty much serves the exact
same purpose you're trying to write code
out of small pieces where each piece
does one thing and does it well
right that's not a new concept that's
the UNIX philosophy that's been around
for ages you break things up into
modules so that you can reuse your code
just like a function you write the
function once you can now use it in 20
places in your codebase same thing with
modules you use it so that you can
compose your code in other words you can
build more complicated things out of
simpler pieces so you create a simple
module that does X in a simple module
that does Y and then you can combine the
two of them together to do something
more complicated which is you know X and
wire x times y you do it to hide
complexity so you know you can have a
very simple function that under the hood
does something truly complicated and
difficult and all of your users benefit
from you know a single one-liner to do
something that's actually pretty hard
same thing with modules you create
modules to encapsulate to abstract away
really complicated infrastructure and
modules also tend to be a really good
abstraction layer for testing as well so
with general-purpose languages functions
you would write a bunch of unit tests
for them it's a good way to build your
code out of these really battle-tested
understood pieces it's the same thing
with modules if you build your code out
of small modules and you test each of
those modules then you're building on
top of these really solid building
blocks these are some of the same
reasons why people use functions and
classes in pretty much any language
exactly yeah I mean it's it's
infrastructures code code is code and a
lot pretty much all the same principles
you'd use in Java or Python or Ruby are
going to apply to terraform and almost
any other infrastructures code tool
another concept we have from software
engineering is layering how does that
fit into the terraform world in in a
pretty similar manner in the sense that
typically with modules you'll have I
will say that the term module is a
little overloaded in programming in
general but in in the terraform context
specifically so module can be used to
refer to maybe I describe it as a
generic module so that's something that
does some type of infrastructure but
it's not specific to some
use-case so maybe you have a module that
deploys a single server or a group of
five servers and there's nothing
specific about it that's just a generic
way that your company is gonna run this
group of five servers and maybe they'll
be highly available and scalable and
have certain types of monitoring already
configured for them then a layer above
that is you can start building modules
that are a little more use case specific
so maybe you create a micro service
module that takes that cluster module
maybe it adds a load balancer module
maybe it adds a database module and this
is how your company runs a micro service
and then finally at the layer above that
you can have a root module is
technically the turbine terraform and
that's the actual thing you deploy and
that's going to be very very use case
specific so that'll be a root module to
deploy service food maybe your search
service at your company and another
module to deploy your my sequel database
and another root module to deploy your
network topology so you essentially just
like you might combine functions and
classes and layer things together in any
general-purpose programming language you
can do the same thing in terraform and
layer together these pieces to gradually
build up complexity module is a keyword
and terraform that provides a specific
way to reuse code layering is a design
pattern where you divide your system up
from top to bottom so to each layer
communicates with adjacent layers now
you probably an example in your book or
one of your talks I forget of building
out a vault implementation vault being a
hash your core product how do you go
about breaking something down into
layers
which go from bottom to top and reusable
modules that you might call multiple
times to compose things horizontally
yeah that's absolutely right so module
is overloaded unfortunately so module is
a key word in terraform like language
and when you use it you can basically
say hey go find the code in this folder
or the skit repo and run it module is
also used to refer to the thing you
deploy it's also used to refer to other
things so it's unfortunately a slightly
confusing term but your layering is more
of a design pattern if we look at a
concrete example like vault so what is
vault vault is an open source tool from
Hoshi Corp for storing secrets things
like database passwords TLS certificates
API keys anything you don't want the bad
guys getting and it runs as a
distributed system so you typically run
three or five vault servers and those
typically talk to three or five console
servers to store the actual underlying
data and so it's actually two
distributed systems you're running so we
built a set of modules to run vault we
did that in partnership with Tasha Corp
and the way we design them if you
actually go look at the code is if there
isn't just one super magical vault
module that does everything fault
instead it actually consists of a bunch
of small little pieces that each do
different pieces of this vault equation
so for example one of those pieces can
spit up a ball to cluster in other words
those three or five servers specifically
to run vault another piece can spin up a
load balancer some customers use load
balancers with vaults some do not some
talk directly to the underlying nodes
there's another module for the security
group rule in other words the firewall
rules that control what traffic can go
in and out of Ault another one that
controls
I am permissions which is the things the
vault nodes are allowed to do and the
reason we have these all the separate
pieces as separate modules is that
depending on how you're deploying vault
you will want to be able to combine and
compose those things in different ways
and I don't mean just across totally
different companies I mean even within a
single company so that the canonical
example is in production you run vaults
the way I mentioned
earlier three servers for vault three
servers for consul in a pre-production
environment that's a bit expensive and
you don't need that much scalability and
high availability so you might want to
co-locate vault and console onto the
same cluster of servers or maybe even
just a single server and if vault was
one super module there'd be no way to do
that but because the security group
rules are separate because the AI and
permissions are separate because the
load balancers separate now we can
choose to combine those pieces with the
separate pieces of the console code that
we've written and so you can use the
same code in different environments in
different ways you might also run it in
different ways between a PCI environment
and non PCI etc so by building it out of
these little pieces you can then layer
them together to meet different use
cases if I understand you're saying
these reusable components their building
blocks and you combine them but maybe
parameterize them a bit differently in
order to create the whole and you might
combine them differently or with
different sets of parameters to do a
similar thing in different environments
exactly yeah and this ties again into a
lot of software engineering practices
you're gonna see with other languages
right you create functions you create
classes but you also do things like
dependency injection we're in a
general-purpose language you know
instead of the class that you wrote
deciding I'm gonna talk to a my sequel
database you pass that in as a parameter
to this class and so with infrastructure
code you can do the same thing the vault
code for example takes in as an input
parameter what VPC to run it in other
words the networking setup where it's
going to live rather than just assuming
or creating one itself you can pass one
in and that way you can run it in
different V pcs you're not subject to
some very specific way that that code
designed it it's actually something you
can control you can inject turns out
that also really comes in handy both
with general-purpose language where you
can then inject mock dependencies rather
than the real ones and you can do the
same thing with infrastructure code you
can use some default V PC that use for
testing rather than a production one at
test time I do want to come back to
testing I want to talk a bit about the
idea of a V PC in some of the examples
you have a module that
defines a V PC and that functions in the
design sense as a layer and then you put
your components in the V PC so you're
building up your final system in
layering can you explain thought process
around that yes so there's actually
something else that comes in that is a
little more specific to infrastructure
code that's also worth considerate so
the V PC for folks that are new to this
that's your basic networking setup in
usually in the cloud every cloud has its
own different types of e pcs that stands
for virtual private cloud and it
consists of things like subnets and
route tables and basically figures out
IP addresses and what IP addresses can
talk to what other IP addresses so the V
PC is usually one of the very very first
things you're gonna create inside of
your AWS GCP Azure account and then
you're going to deploy everything else
into the V PC and that way when you
deploy a server into it that server gets
assigned a reasonable IP address so one
of the things that tends to happen is
the V PC is probably something you're
going to deploy once and you probably
aren't gonna touch it a whole lot
you know maybe you'll update it once a
year or something like that it might sit
there for years without you having to do
anything to it whereas the things you
deploy into the V PC are gonna change
much more frequently right if you deploy
your docker eyes to happen to the V PC
that might change you might redeploy
that 20 times a day so one of the other
interesting things about separating your
code into these different modules is and
this is again part of the overloaded
terminology so this is actually
specifically route modules these are the
ones where you actually run terraform
apply to deploy them is you might want
to separate the V PC route module from
other things because if they're together
and this is actually a really common
mistake people who are new to terraform
new to almost any infrastructures code
tool is they tend to shove all their
code into a single file or a single
folder basic a single module and that
code grows and grows and grows ask all
your environments all of your different
types of infrastructure all in one place
and that has a huge huge number of
downsides if all of your code is in one
place it is going to be slow
you know running terraform planner
replied could take twenty minutes or
just the plan even just to fetch the
data about all of that infrastructure
its insecure because now if anybody
wants to change that code they have to
have permissions to everything in that
code it's hard to understand and review
because it's just a huge amount of code
and even if you run terraform plan it's
a giant output that nobody really looks
at it's hard to test
I mean infrastructure testing is hard
anyway but testing a large amount of
infrastructure is borderline impossible
in any automated sense and most
importantly it's extremely risky if you
have your VP C code in the same place as
the app you deployed 20 times per day
and 20 times per day you put your VP C
at risk of some sloppy little thing you
know some little typo some silly mistake
and you could blow away your entire
network topology and everything running
in it and there's just no reason to do
that and so this is something specific
to infrastructure right because mistakes
with infrastructure tend to be more
costly than mistakes with applications
you have a bug in your application most
of the time it's pretty harmless you
deploy an old version or a new version
you're good to go you mess something up
in your infrastructure and your company
could be out of business so the mistakes
are costly and so you do a little more
thinking about how to isolate your code
how to separate different things and so
one way to do that with terraform is to
deploy these things in separate route
modules and so the VPC is at one route
module your apps earn another one when
you deploy them the permissions you need
to access them can be different they are
the state that terraform stores about
this infrastructure is stored in
separate files
you can have different approval and code
review and testing practices for each
one and so you can basically separate
things out to essentially control your
level of risk and so that way you can go
and deploy your app 20 times a day
and not have any worries that you're
accidentally gonna blow way of EPC
there's a number of benefits to this
approach you're talking about
for one thing security and that everyone
doesn't need to have permission to
everything and then there's the
efficiency that when you deploy your
service it doesn't have to do a
verification of the State against a
thousand pieces of infrastructure which
you as a engineer who's building one
service are not in ten
to change those things anyway right
right exactly
it's I mean don't put all your eggs in
one basket right this there's nothing
new here it's it's something humans have
known for a long time
it's just tempting to do it with
infrastructure code because it's new and
we don't understand it as well but if
you find yourself with you know 20,000
lines of infrastructure code and one
file or in one folder and it's all
running together and plan is taking ten
minutes you should probably refactor and
change that because you're in you're
gonna have a bad day sooner or later
from that I think we are going I could
go with this discussion is talking about
a micro-services architecture which is
increasingly popular the way terraform
works it runs all the terraform files in
the directory where it runs so you have
different code bases which are either in
different get repos are just different
directories what is a recommended
structure for an organization that is
delivering a micro services architecture
yeah micro service is interesting it has
some of the same trade-offs right what
what are the reasons to do micro
services one because you read about it
and it's a buzzword you think it's cool
that's probably a pretty bad reason the
actual reasons to do micro services are
things like you need to scale your teams
actually it's not even a technical thing
it's extra social thing right because
you have a bunch of people and they you
know having 10,000 developers working on
a single app is pretty hard they end up
stepping on each other they someone a
lot of tests things someone or just push
a hundred times a day without any
testing so allowing teams to own
separate services and to go at their own
pace and control their own coding
practices that's a really nice benefit
of micro services and the same thing may
apply to infrastructure code right you
could have one team that's responsible
for the VPC and they have their own
coding practices and their own testing
practices and they can use those and you
have a separate team responsible for a
certain micro service or a database and
they can use different practices another
reason to break things up is so you can
use different technologies with micro
services right you can write one in
JavaScript and one in Python and one in
Java and one in Ruby that one probably
doesn't apply quite as much to the
terraform world because you're probably
using terraform here and terraform there
but it could
so one of the patterns for example that
you might see is you might use terraform
for example to deploy kubernetes so the
actual servers like the worker nodes the
control plane for this orchestration
tool for docker but then you use cube
control or helm or some other tool to
actually deploy the docker containers on
top of kubernetes so there you're using
two separate tools by basically
separating things out the third reason
to use micro services in the world is
for different scalability requirements
so you have one service that needs a lot
of memory another one that needs a lot
of CPU one that scales vertically one of
the skills for Zonta ly so breaking
those out separately allows you to scale
them each individually and appropriate
to whatever needs they have whereas if
they're on in one giant model if you
can't do that that one probably applies
the least to terraform code terraform
code you break out mostly to maintain
risk which is by the way another
interesting property of micro services
when you do them correctly is one part
you know one micro service could go down
and if you've built your micro services
correctly the others can keep running
and function and that's fine and that's
the same idea with separate root modules
in terraform is if you blow something up
at one module you kind of limit the
blast radius so it doesn't affect all
the infrastructure and the other modules
if you're running microservices using
terraform how you organize the code as
always the answer is it depends but the
general idea here is you want to keep
those factors in mind is do the teams
that own those micro services need to
run separately and at their own pace so
if one is deploying using terraform 30
times a day and one deploys one time a
year that would be a good reason to
separate out their terraform code
another one comes down to the risk
tolerance of what happens if things go
wrong if you have one module that has
your micro service that processes
payments and you have one that prot has
like a front-end funny widget that you
put up for april fools then maybe the
one when you're updating the one for
april fools you take down your whole
payment system that probably isn't a
good way to manage risk you may want to
separate those micro services out so
factors like that or what you would keep
in mind in terms of how you organize the
code but just as with micro services
to keep in mind is it's a balance
micro-services have a cost and it's
actually a very very significant cost
and similarly having a ton of tariffs or
modules also has a cost it's more stuff
to manage you basically have to connect
modules together which isn't the easiest
thing in the world to do if you have to
deploy a new environment it's easier to
deploy it when it's just one in module
versus 300 so it's a balance you don't
want to go crazy and have 8,000
terraform modules per environment just
like you probably shouldn't have 8,000
micro services per environment so strike
a reasonable balance in terms of like
risk tolerance and how your teams are
operating calling all developers there's
no telling what you can create when you
upgrade your data platform to inner
systems iris are you ready to build the
applications you want however you want
them are you ready to develop
applications faster than ever
collaborate build faster and deploy more
efficiently
tomorrow's next breakthroughs are
waiting for you today inner systems iris
data platform ready set code start
coding for free visit inner systems.com
slash try to try iris we recently
published a show on data management in
the world of micro services some micro
services are necessarily going to be
stateful and they may require some kind
of storage infrastructure each micro
service may use a different type of data
management one might be relational one
might be a key value store and the micro
services they need some infrastructure
to run on do you have any thoughts on a
couple different structures for teams
one would be you have the terraform code
separate DevOps engineers are deploying
that the team that's building micro
service they need a dynamo DB so they
communicate DevOps that helps pushes it
out and they deploy their code or option
B is you have maybe an embedded DevOps
engineer in the micro Service team or
maybe developers learn a bit of
terraform and they manage their own
infrastructure and they push it out as
part of an integrated deploy along with
their code what are your thoughts on
those two options yeah we've seen a few
different patterns again the the boring
answer here is
it depends but the the more interesting
answer is probably the most effective
pattern we've seen is if central team
can build up a considerable amount of
expertise around terraform and whatever
type of infrastructure you using so
maybe that's AWS for Google Cloud or
asher and it takes actually a wild to
build up that expert expertise to
understand whether things should run on
ec2 instances versus docker container
versus lambda functions how do you
secure these things how do you do the
monitoring for them it's it's a lot of
stuff to learn and so often the pattern
that we've seen work pretty well is a
central team builds up that expertise
and creates a bunch of reusable modules
that implement the basic requirements
for this company so if your company has
to be PCI compliant or HIPAA compliant
you know the modules will implement
those requirements and will only use
services that are valid for those
constraints and you know if you're using
kubernetes the team will write code that
deploys to kubernetes the way that your
company wants to deploy here running on
top of VMs and auto scaling groups the
modules will do that so you create these
basic set of reusable building blocks
that are well tested well thought-out
and basically have the guardrails in
place and then you hand those to the
other teams to then basically do a
self-service kind of a setup where they
can then use that to deploy their apps
they have some ability to customize
things as they need it
they're not completely dependent on this
one centralized team being a bottleneck
but under the hood they're still
fulfilling the basic requirements for
your company and how much of a central
team you need tends to increase with the
size of the company so if you're a
three-person startup well honestly you
probably a should be using micro
services and B you should probably be on
Heroku or something like that and not
AWS but if you're let's say a 10 person
startup you probably don't need you know
more than like a single person who
spends up a few basic things and then
everybody else uses those pieces and
deploys with them but if you're a 10000
person company you probably want to have
a significant team that really thinks
through these things and then gives this
nice menu the Service Catalog
essentially of reusable code to the rest
of the company to use and then the rest
of the company uses that to then spit up
their micro-services spit up whatever as
they need to and you can all be happy
that things are working more or less
as attended might change directions here
a bit move on to another software
engineering concept the idea of releases
how do you advocate the use of releases
in infrastructure as code I'll explain
how we do it at my company I let you
walk through the whole process so all
the code we write goes through pull
requests so any change you make you
spend up a new branch make your changes
and then submit a port request back to
master all the code gets reviewed and
all of the code goes through our suite
of automated tests and assuming the code
review goes well and the tests all pass
you then merge the code to master and
then we do a release now what we mean by
releases github has a thing called a
release but under the hood it's a get
tagged so we're basically creating a tag
pointing at that commit that we just
merge to master and that tag has a
version number and we use semantic
versioning so it's version X dot y dot C
and we try to use that version number to
communicate whether the change is
backwards compatible or not in the case
of terraform for example if you had a
module that used to create a certain
resource and now it doesn't that would
be a backwards incompatible change or if
you had a module that took in a certain
input variable and it no longer does
again that's a backwards incompatible
change any consumer of that module now
has to update their code in a
non-trivial way in order to use the new
version so we do this release we create
this get tagged with a version number as
well as some release notes migration
instructions if you need them and now
this code is available for use so in the
case I mentioned before with the central
DevOps team building out a library of
code for the rest of the company to use
that team could do the same thing they
could create their micro service module
version 0.01 and then a few teams deploy
with that and then the ops team improves
something of the module and they
released zero zero two now the rest of
the company can pick up the new version
and hopefully all they need to do to do
that is just a bump a version numbered
from 0 1 to 0 2 so it should be easy and
you would roll this out by promoting
that change from environment to
environment so you would take version
zero zero two and you would deploy it
and let's say your dev environment
that make sure it seems to work there's
no issues if that works you then take
the exact same code that's zero zero two
and you put it in staging again
test test test everything looks good
finally you take the exact same version
and put it in production and this is a
mutable infrastructure so you these
immutable artifacts these tags ensure
that you're running the exact same code
in all of these environments which gives
you a slightly better chance that if it
works in one it'll probably work in the
next one so that's our typical release
process now suppose in production we are
running ten different micro services
your module does something that is
common let's say it spins up a load
balancer all your micro services need a
load balancer and you you said
previously you may have the one that
releases 30 times a day and the one that
releases once a month is it necessary
that everybody upgrade to zero zero two
right around the same time or can we
slow roll it out this is the the classic
question that I think every company runs
into not just with infrastructure code
but with anything if you have an
internal code base of Java libraries
that you share within your company
you're gonna have the same question does
everybody update to the new you know
security library now or do we do it one
at a time this happens all over the
place the answer comes down to as always
it depends um so what does it depend on
one factor is what kind of a change
isn't if for example the central team
released a security patch and it's
patching something critical from a
security perspective you of course want
everybody to pick up that change is soon
as humanly possible if it's something a
lot more minor then it's less critical
that you do it immediately and now comes
down to what are the trade-offs if
people don't pick up the change
immediately the advantages they're able
to focus on whatever they were doing
originally you know shipping product for
example rather than updating their
infrastructure which the product team
might like but on the other hand if you
have some versions of the services that
are now way way way behind then it's
gonna be harder to catch them up they're
gonna be out of date and when that
inevitable security patch does come out
it'll be really hard to get that team up
to date so it's a balance as always do
you want to pay off tech debt do you
want to ship product
what is your team going to prioritize
generally if you're using Symantec
you can probably if your tests are good
you can probably safely update patch
versions maybe even automatically so if
your central team goes from zero zero
one two zero zero two you can maybe push
that change out immediately to everyone
if your testing is good enough and it's
a backwards compatible change so that
shouldn't do too much damage but
anything beyond that is gonna take
testing it's gonna take time to roll out
and that's where you're gonna have to
make a business decision that's really
what it comes down to it is common in
the world of server configuration
management the puppet chef ansible that
you would run those tools on a server
every say 30 minutes and any changes
that anybody makes manually would simply
get overwritten do you have a key that
was terraform
and it is a way to really enforce that
infrastructure as code culture where any
changes you make are going to be
overwritten or do you have to keep more
of what we see me talking about which is
release is where we say we have a change
we are going to decide to put that
change out now or tomorrow yeah
with tools like chef and puppet running
every 30 minutes or what have you the
reason that works and occasionally that
causes its own issues but for the most
part it works is because we're changing
the configuration on an existing server
right you're updating some dependency on
your linux box and most of the time
that'll work okay and even if it doesn't
the damage will usually be not
catastrophic with terraform code what
you're managing with that code is the
server itself as well as the network it
runs on in the database next to it and
the load balancer and all your DNS
entries and everything else and so the
cost of getting it wrong there is a lot
higher so the trade-offs are different
if you were to automatically push out
some DNS change and you could
conceivably make your entire website and
accessible if there was a small book if
you automatically were to roll out
database changes you might delete your
company's data so generally speaking I
think the applying terraform every 30
minutes is not a pattern that you're
gonna see very often just because the
cost of getting it wrong is really high
what you might want to do on a regular
basis is run the terraform plan
and what that will show you is the
difference between what's actually
deployed in the wild and what your code
says is deployed and if the plan
basically shows any difference that you
weren't expecting that probably means
something is out of date somebody did
make a change by hand or there's some
kind of issue going on and that's a good
way to gauge the health of your code but
ultimately fixing it is still going to
be a human being having to make a
decision and say hey the reason there's
a difference here is actually legitimate
and we shouldn't do anything about it or
oh whoops I you know tweak this manually
and forgot to sync up and let me go fix
it and you can create alerts around that
you can actually do things to detect it
but I don't know that I would I
personally would not have confidence in
Auto applying every 30 minutes I think
that's gonna end up with a lot of really
uncomfortable discussions with your CEO
when data starts disappearing or the
site goes down yeah I have seen certain
amount of cows called even my puppet
being applied on a continuous basis so
moving on another best practice from
software engineering is code reviews how
can code reviews be applied to
infrastructure as code projects more or
less in a similar manner to code reviews
on any other kind of project which is
first thing you do is you create a
culture where you decide what requires
review you could simply decide all code
changes require review or maybe certain
parts of the code based that's up to
your company that's another good
business decision to make once you've
decided it you need a code review tool
if you're using github or gitlab
bitbucket all of these now support a
pull request or merge request process
which inherently includes a code review
so you typically don't need separate
tools these days for that next thing
you'd probably want to take care of is
to determine these standards right you
don't want people just code reviewing
randomly because that means one person
will do a review and will nitpick every
tiny little minor thing that's totally
relevant and then the next person will
just say ship into every single PR
without looking at it come up with some
standards for what the team is looking
for one of them could be things like
does this thing have automated tests
right that could be a human being say no
tests not going to give it a shipping
does this thing have documentation or
example code or comments or some way for
new to figure out how to use this code
something that should be part of your
standard is the codes style but you
probably don't want a human being
enforcing that you want to use an
automated tool so in the case of
terraform you can automatically run
terraform format it's just one of the
commands built in and that'll
automatically style the code in a
certain pattern that's consistent across
your code base you definitely don't want
to spend time arguing over curly brace
prey placement or anything like that so
all of that I think is very common with
almost any language the only I think
special thing about terraform that you
might do differently in your code review
process is to include the output of the
terraform plan command as part of what
you review so you're reviewing not just
the changes but also Tara forms output
which shows you what those changes are
going to do to the live environment and
those changes the output of terraform
plan they look a little bit like a get
diff so they have like pluses and
minuses and tilde is to say something is
being added removed or modified and
those are really nice to have as part of
your code review process because then
you might see you know a big red minus
sign next to your database and say wait
a minute wait a minute don't ship that
thing that that's not going to end well
so making plan part of your code agree
process is I think somewhat unique to
terraform what it looks like in practice
if you set up a nice pipe light around
terraform is team member will for
example put up a pull request with a
change to your dev environment and you
might get like a slack notification that
says hey here's the pull request and
here's the plan output do you want to
approve these and you could you know
click a button and slack or whatever
tool you're using that approves it then
that change goes out you test that make
sure it works then you repeat the same
process in staging and then you repeat
the same process in prod and every step
of the way you're checking the plan
output and the code changes and you
might notice again here that we're being
extra cautious with our infrastructure
changes right if you were for example
rolling out a new version of an app you
probably don't need a human being
approving the rollout to your kubernetes
cluster your auto scaling group every
time because those rollouts almost
always look the same and if they go bad
it's pretty easy to rollback
but again infrastructure has a cost of
getting it wrong that's quite a bit
higher and so that's why you want a
human being to use a little bit of
judgment to look at
these plan outputs and say okay yes this
should ship to prod this probably isn't
gonna do anything to catastrophic so
build that into your pipeline and build
that into your code review process and
you can sleep a little more in the
evenings if getting if I was gonna start
a task in any programming language and I
need to do things like talk to a
database or manipulate date and time I'm
not gonna code that all up from scratch
I'm gonna type into Google what's best
library and Python for database client
or whatever it is I'm trying to do I
thought even in working with puppet
there are puppet libraries for almost
any type of server you might might want
to manage you may want to modify that
library but it's still gonna save you a
lot of time versus starting from scratch
where are we in the terraform world in
terms of reusable open source ecosystems
so terraform has something called the
terraformed registry which is a
collection of open source reusable
terraform code very similar to probably
what you're mentioning there's I think
the puppet Forge
there's ansible galaxy there's chef
supermarket there's a bunch of these
collections of open source repos to be
honest the quality of the code in those
is a mixed bag some of it works
beautifully and it saves you a ton of
time but a unfortunately high percentage
of it it's a much higher percentage of
it than you'll find for example in NPM
for JavaScript or in Ruby gems for the
Ruby world or in maven for Java I think
a much higher percentage of
infrastructure code has issues a lot of
it just does not work at all like you
run it and it just doesn't do the thing
it says it'll do it's completely broken
a large percentage of it is very very
hard coded to one specific use case and
might not fit what you're trying to do
and I'd say an astonishingly high
percentage of it has no documentation
and no automated tests so
to me that's a bit of a problem and
before I started grunt work actually we
spent a lot of time looking at all of
these trying to use them I've tried to
use them in my previous projects and my
success rate has not been great and is
still not great to this day and I think
the biggest issue is is exactly that
there's really two core problems with a
lot of the open source code one is the
lack of automated tests automated tests
for infrastructure code are hard to
write they're hard to maintain and most
of them are actually integration tests
that have to deploy into a real Google
or Amazon account or a sure
and so they cost money and most people
just don't want to spend money on their
little open source project so most of
those projects have no testing at all
the second major issue is a lot of them
are not meant to be used directly in
production they're meant to do exactly
what you mentioned which is you're
supposed to copy and paste them and then
adapt them and then you basically never
touch the open source repo again which
means you don't have this feedback cycle
of people using it on a long-term basis
getting updates getting new versions
because that's not how you consume most
libraries right if you're using Java
you're pulling in jars from maven at a
specific version if you're using Ruby
you're pulling in Ruby gems at a
specific version if you're using node
you're pulling in libraries from NPM and
specific version and occasionally you
bump those version numbers you're not
pulling in the raw source code and
modifying it in place that's not the
normal way to use open source code
unfortunately a lot of the
infrastructure code out there is
designed for pull it in copy and paste
they basically fork the open source repo
and then never you know rejoin it again
so there's a bunch of issues at my
company of grunt work the stuff we
open-source we do try to work around a
lot of that stuff so we do try to test
that we do try to document it is
designed for use directly in production
via a version URL but it's still I'd say
the ecosystem is still developing to say
the least so it's still pretty hard to
just quickly Google something you know I
need distributed system X I don't want
to spend six months you know building
that myself can I find it off the shelf
it's hit or miss it's very hit or miss
go back to the Python example I think
every Python program that wants to
connect to my sequel pretty much wants
to connect to my sequel in the same way
the sequel statements you send will be
different but there isn't generally a
problem of this sequel client library
doesn't connect to my sequel the way I
want it to now is it the case in
building infrastructure that everybody's
needs are if not the same at least the
differences can be expressed maybe
through choice of parameters or do
people build infrastructure in
sufficiently different ways that it's
just hard to come up with a reusable
module that will be generally useful I
think there is just as much overlap and
how people use infrastructure as there
is an almost any other kind of
programming you're never gonna have a
module that fits a hundred percent of
use cases just like you're never gonna
have a java library that fits a hundred
percent of use cases but 80 90 plus
percent I think is very likely I think
the the issue is you have to design it
the right way and you have to take into
account for the fact that the tools are
a little more primitive than what we're
used to write Java for example in most
major programming languages have the
concept of first-class dependency
management right you use you know Gradle
or maven or some build system in your
java code or use package.json on your
node code and you can say I want this
dependency at this version and it pulls
it in it pulls in transitive
dependencies you can update them you can
use them your IDE recognizes them right
there's this whole ecosystem that's
developed over decades to make it easy
to use these off-the-shelf library's
most infrastructures code tools just
haven't had decades and 'muslim just
haven't developed this ecosystem this
idea of dependency management the ski
thoses of testing and all the other
ingredients that you need to make the
code solid and usable off-the-shelf and
you know if you look at the open source
world in the early days nobody trusts
that any open source code right it was
you know companies didn't use that stuff
in production that's garbage right it's
it's crap but a few decades later we
figured out how to build the stuff how
to test it how to version it how to
release it and now it you'd be silly not
to use open source code in your project
I think the exact same thing will happen
at the infrastructure world it's just
going to take time and I think the code
is just as reusable your company
Bush's open-source reasonable libraries
we pick one example of one of these
libraries to talk about what it does and
what is the value proposition sure yeah
so the company is grunt work and the the
focus is on exactly this problem is
creating reusable infrastructure code
because the reality is most companies go
into production on Google on Google
cloud on AWS on Azure the infrastructure
you need under the hood is gonna look
pretty darn similar you're gonna use it
in a million different ways but under
the hood you all need that VPC thing we
talked about earlier you'll all going to
need a database some sort of cluster to
run your workloads like kubernetes load
balancing DNS CI CD pipeline's
monitoring alerting etc that long long
list of things and so we create a bunch
of reusable code for that some of that
code we've open-sourced one of the
examples actually we brought up earlier
which is the Hashi Corp vault so a bunch
of reusable code to run vault this
secrets management solution on AWS on
Google Cloud and on Asscher and the code
will for example spin up a bold cluster
it will actually even before that it'll
give you code to install vault on a
Linux server and we typically recommend
running this code in packer template
this is another open-source tool
basically lets you create a virtual
machine image with vault and all of its
dependencies already installed and
configured then we give you code to run
a cluster of servers and you would run
your virtual machine on those servers so
now you have a bunch of servers with
vault on it there's a script that we
provide to then bootstrap those servers
so they can discover each other and
connect and form a nice little cluster
for you there's code there that shows
you how to automatically unseal the
vault servers that they're actually able
to access the secret data that they're
storing there's code talk up load
balancers that code to deal with TLS
certificates on the nodes they can all
speak to each other over an encrypted
connection and so on and so forth so
this code gives you a bunch of these
building blocks to run fault and instead
of spending two three months learning
how to run it learning how to secure
learning how to scale it and all these
other pieces you can basically grab
these this code off the shelf
use it had a specific version directly
from the repo and get vault up and
running in a day and overtime saves a
huge amount of maintenance as vault
changes as terraform changes its AWS
changes you basically get all of that
through version releases so it saves you
a lot of time over the long run as well
you mentioned in I believe it's one of
your talks about these open source
repositories being battle-hardened and
production-ready that comes about from
the feedback cycle over time of people
using these people in the community
submit PR as you see how to improve them
could you give me an example of a
modification that you made from the
original version of a library and the
version you have now that solve some
kind of production issue or otherwise
improved the code yeah there's there's
been up a bunch we've been maintaining
this code now for probably four years
it's been used in production by hundreds
of companies and so there's been lots of
interesting stories
I mean bit but the simplest one to
understand is just the fact that you
know we've talked a few times that a lot
of the DevOps tooling is new and so it's
evolving and changing very very quickly
the code that you wrote that works with
terraform version eight that was out two
years ago does not work anymore with
version 12 which is out now so one of
the biggest things we did is the library
of code is you know 300,000 plus lines
of code is updating all of that code to
work with terraform 12 that was a huge
massive change that took months but we
do it once and then everybody benefits
one of the other ones that I fondly and
not so fondly remembers working on the
elasticsearch code we actually caught
some bugs just from having automated
tests so our automated tests they spin
up the ELCA cluster or actually about 20
L clusters and a whole bunch of
different configurations and make sure
that we can write data read data etc and
at one point we noticed that the tests
were passing just fine in u.s. East one
but our test code randomly picks other
AWS regions and so they were failing in
other regions so we found a couple bugs
not in our code but actually in
elasticsearch itself where some of the
discovery
that they had was hard-coded to use us
east one and you know there's a dozen
stories we found issues with how Cabana
used TLS and we had to check out the
code and actually like modified source
code to find out what was going on and
there's a certain type of TLS
certificate that it just doesn't work
with and you don't get a reasonable
error message and it's it's the kind of
stuff that there's no way to expect it
it's the reason that these software
projects talk takes so long right we're
talking about yak shaving and you think
you're gonna be doing log aggregation
and instead you're you know ten thousand
lines deep and cabana Co dealing with
how they process TLS certificates this
is the stuff that comes from just having
that feedback cycle over a long period
of time evgeny i had plans to spend some
time on testing but we are pretty close
to end of time i do want to tell us
sooner as the book has an extensive
amount of practical tips about testing
infrastructure of code that could even
be the subject of an entire episode and
maybe we'll do that someday i want to
wrap up with where can people find you
on the internet or any anything you want
to point people out if you're interested
in finding me personally in hopefully
not creepy way i have home page which is
why Brickman calm if you google my name
it should be the top result if I've done
my SEO correctly and if you're
interested in learning anything else
about my company and then the work that
we're doing the company's called grunt
work if you google us we should also
come right up but it's a grunt work dot
io now add your book is available in the
usual places where people can purchase
books oh yes thank you for that yep
Amazon and Barnes and Noble and your
local bookstore II should be able to to
find it
yep Kenny it's been a pleasure speaking
with you about infrastructure is code
and thank you for talking to software
engineering radio thank you so so much
for having me it was a lot of fun for
software engineering radio this has been
Robert blumen and thank you for
listening developers take your marks
it's time to upgrade your data platform
to inner systems iris it's time to
deliver complex mission-critical
applications in the fastest route
possible it's time to use any data from
any source it's time to embed analytics
and create interactive user interfaces
so what are you waiting for
choose your language choose your tools
choose your environment collaborates
build faster and deploy more efficiently
done and done tomorrow's next
breakthroughs are waiting for you today
inner system's iris Data Platform the
fastest way to build applications
ready set code start coding for free
visit inner systems.com slash tried to
try iris thanks for listening to Nessie
radio an educational program brought to
you by Archer police software magazine
for more about the podcast including
other episodes visit our website at SC
radio net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of se radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening